Hello.
The next thing we're going to do is set up a2d character that we can play all game, as I will need
to briefly close on our engine and attached in this course, I'm going to provide some assets that we're
going to be using to make our game.
I want you to download them, open up your content and make sure the content folder is selected and
find this photo called individual Sprites and just let and drag it into your Unreal Engine project.
This one for a bunch of sprites that we're going to be using when we set up our 2D character.
So in our project, we're going to be referencing the content draw quite a lot.
So to save some time, I want to go to Window and go content browser and just let content browser one
and this one just make sure that our content browser is always there.
If you don't want it there, then you can just delete it and press control space to quickly open up
your connector or just click it here.
But I kind of like having it there, so I'm just going to add it local window, corner browser and just
like content browser one to make sure it's always there.
Then with all these images selected to save time, just set them all.
So I'm holding shift and setting a lost image.
Right click on them and go spray actions and apply paper to texture settings.
This will just make it so that all the images that we imported are now clear.
Sometimes if we import an image and don't use apply paper, 3D texture things, sometimes they can be
a bit fuzzy.
I want us to select the individual sprite powder and I'm just going to right click and rename this to
be our Warrior animations.
So we're going to be setting up a 2D character and they're going to have many different animations.
Although to start with, we're going to give our character a couple of basic animations and those are
going to be an auto animation of running animation, a jumping animation attachment animation and a
wall sliding animation.
So I want you to head over to the video animation folder.
So this one is called Idol.
And I want you to select all the images.
And right click and go spreadsheet and go create Sprite.
Now that we've created a Sprite out of all these images, we can turn them into a flipbook, which will
kind of play an animation.
So to do that, so that's the first, right?
And then the last right there, just right click on the first one and go create flipbook and just call
this warrior idol.
No, I don't click on him inside her.
As we can see, it's put all the sprites together into this flipbook.
So first it's going to play us our Warrior One Sprite, then our Warrior two Sprite, then our Warrior
three, one, then a warrior for one, and so on.
If you want to change how fast a place this we can go over to here Sprite where it says frames per second.
And if I made something like one, then it's going to happen very slowly.
Or I made this something like 60.
Then it's going to be very, very fast.
So you just use that to adjust the speed of the flip.
I'm just going to make mine eight.
I think that works pretty well and we can just close this.
Next, I want to close this folder and I want us to head over to the working folder.
Sorry.
It's called running.
So we just, um, head over to the run folder, and we're going to do the same thing.
So set all the images right click, go for fractions and create Sprite.
Then I set all the sprites right click and go create Flipbook, and we can just call this word run.
Then I won't ask to head over to the dash folder.
We'll do the same thing.
I'll set all the images right Click Sprite actions.
Create Sprite.
Then I will select all the sprites.
Right click and create a flipbook.
Then we will head over to the jumping order.
So this one jump.
I will select all the images.
Right click Square actions and create Sprite.
Then I'll settle the sprites again and create a flipbook.
So you should be getting pretty used to this now.
We need to go to the folding folder.
Do the same thing.
So we'll settle the images, right click Sprite actions and create Sprite.
And then was that all these sprites and create a flipbook.
And then finally, we just need to head over to the wall sliding folder.
And slept all these images.
Right click fractions and create Sprite and then we'll create a flipbook of all these sprites.
So now we have set up all the animations that our character is going to use in this first section.